Before we continue on to prompt engineeringfor RAG, let's review the steps that led up tothis stage in the process.
Desired knowledgesources are chunked and
embedded in a vectordatabase,
where they're indexed and ableto be searched
using semantic similarity.
A user query is embedded with the same model thencompared to the vectors in the vector database.
This will return several chunks that are the
most similar.
We now have relevant chunks ofthe document ready
to be passed to the languagemodel.
With relevant chunks at hand, we move on tothe pivotal step of passing these search resultsto the language model.
This instructs the modelto use the retrieved information to providea more informed answer to the user's query.
Generating the most accurate, thorough, relevantoutput possible belongs to the realm of promptengineering.
Prompt engineering is the processor art of
designing text instructions
to guide agenerative AI model towards a desired outcome.
Thesimplest form of a RAG prompt structure
is shownon the right.
Below, you'll see a user query, as wellas relevant context related to that query. Answerthe user query using the relevant context.
Here,you'll provide the user query and the relevantcontext, while the generative AI model fills outyour answer.
While this may seem simple there areextra considerations that are worth mentioningwhen designing a RAG system.
The first is that thebasics of prompt
engineering apply strongly here.
Language models perform best with clear,
structuredand organized information.
Some models will comewith system prompts, where you provide separateinstructions outlining the model's generalbehavior.
Other models may require you to embedthese instructions directly into the main contextyou provide them.
The second one is confusing language can be problematic for models and peopletoo,
so it's crucial to communicate clearly andconcisely.
In particular, models perform better with
positive wording, i.e. instructing the model to dothis,
than with negative wording, i.e. instructing
the model to not do this.
In addition to beingclear and concise, providing a complete example ofa desired output,
also known as one-shot learning,
can improve model outputs.
Many models includingstate-of-the-art models such as GPT4 and Claw 3Opus respond well to XML style formatting.
XML isa well-organized structure with sections for wherecertain information goes
that is defined by itsopening and
closing tags using angle braces.
Thismakes it super clear to the model where the startand end of each relevant section is.
On the rightside of the slide, you'll see the previous RAGprompt reformatted to XML
with the instructions, user query,
and relevant context sectioned out.
Mention in the prompt that certain
informationmay not be relevant.
If the language model thinksit must use all the information provided, it couldlead to hallucinations when irrelevant detailsare included.
Similarly, it helps to explicitlytell the model to admit when it doesn't havethe information it needs to answer the question.
Consider including metadata about the sourcedocuments to provide context, especially whenusing information from multiple sources.
Forexample, you can include the following in theprompt to inform the language model what type ofdata it's using.
Provided below is a user queryand
some relevant information.
You'll first seea summary of the source from which the relevantinformation comes from,
then a direct passage fromthe source.
Use information from the direct passageto inform your answer, contextualizing it with thesummary.
However, using XML is not necessary to usethese techniques.
The vital point is that thetext should be clearly structured. XML is just onepopular example of such a structure.
Another goodreason to include chunk metadata in the prompt isthat it allows the LLM to cite its sources.
The newprompt will include the instructions to cite thesource title and author, along with more contextualinformation
that includes source title and sourceauthor.
Provided below is a user query with somerelevant information. You'll first see adirect passage from the source,
then the sourcetitle and source author.
Use information fromchunk y's direct passage to
inform your answer
and then cite the source title and
author atthe end of the answer.
Finally, prompt engineeringis a series of trial and error. Be ready to tweakand test the prompt over time.
Language modelscan update and change behavior.
Your source datamay change or the requirements of your applicationmay evolve over time.
Whatever it is it is rarely aone-size-fits-all solution.
It may be a good ideato invent a testing system whereby you can gradethe quality of various prompts and the answersthey offer.
That concludes what you'll need toknow about
prompt engineering for RAG.
Coming upnext, you'll take what you learned and apply itby writing prompts that effectively use the vectordatabases search results
to answer user questions.